<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>South Dakota Code Camp</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/</link><description>Recent content on South Dakota Code Camp</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adam Barney</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/adam-barney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/adam-barney/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Brian Matherly</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/brian-matherly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/brian-matherly/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ivan Ven Osdel</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/ivan-ven-osdel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/ivan-ven-osdel/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Joel Kauffman</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/joel-kauffman/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/joel-kauffman/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Ken Versaw</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/ken-versaw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/ken-versaw/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kevin Logan</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/kevin-logan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/kevin-logan/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a developer at Omnitech for 8 and a half years. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on several projects and my current one relies heavily on unit testing and Selenium UI automation that are executed in builds to verify functionality before manual testing. I also enjoy working with web client UX technologies. I blog at http://geekswithblogs.net/aligned/Default.aspx, email me at klogan@omnitech-inc.com or my Twitter handle is @logk34.</description></item><item><title>Kwen Peterson</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/kwen-peterson/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/kwen-peterson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Matthew Weier Ophinney</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/matthew-weier-ophinney/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/matthew-weier-ophinney/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Miles Rausch</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/miles-rausch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/miles-rausch/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sam Otis</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/sam-otis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/sam-otis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Savannah Boedigheimer</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/savannah-boedigheimer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/savannah-boedigheimer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Seth Larson</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/seth-larson/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/seth-larson/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Thomas Meier</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/thomas-meier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/thomas-meier/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bryan Burgers</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/bryan-burgers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/bryan-burgers/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jackson Murtha</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/jackson-murtha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/jackson-murtha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Robert Boedigheimer</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/robert-boedigheimer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 16:31:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/robert-boedigheimer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>An Introduction to Clojure</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/an-introduction-to-clojure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/an-introduction-to-clojure/</guid><description>Clojure is a functional, general purpose, LISP style language originally targeting the Java Virtual Machine. With almost no syntax and sticking close to theoretical and mathematical models of computation, it can be hard for one to see how Clojure might work in the wild. We will review Clojure and some of its capabilities—then take a look at some of the gritty details when building a web application.</description></item><item><title>Smarter Responsive Design</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/smarter-responsive-design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/smarter-responsive-design/</guid><description>Sam looks beyond stacking and single-column layouts and into the messy responsive needs of navigation, carousels, and other tricky web practices with thoughts on how we can improve the user experience on mobile devices.</description></item><item><title>A Principled Approach to Software Management</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/a-principled-approach-to-software-management/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/a-principled-approach-to-software-management/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered why sometimes great software engineers become bad software managers? In school we learned the practices of software management: estimating, planning, process improvement and lifecycle management. But software management is more about the people you work with than the processes you use. In this session, Brian Matherly will discuss some of the principles that he holds as an engineering manager. If you are a practicing software manager, come to be encouraged and maybe pick up some new tips.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography 101</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/cryptography-101/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/cryptography-101/</guid><description>Learn the &amp;ldquo;black art&amp;rdquo; of cryptography, including public/private and symmetric encryption, hashing, and digital signatures. Review the basics of cryptography and what techniques are appropriate for various situations. Discover practical techniques for securing content received on public web sites.</description></item><item><title>Electronics 101 for IoT Developers</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/electronics-101-for-iot-developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/electronics-101-for-iot-developers/</guid><description>Making the leap in to IoT development used to be riddled with obstacles, ranging from choices of programming languages to cost and features of development boards to the pain of getting these devices and your development machines imaged and set up for development. Most of these obstacles have been addressed by the growing community of IoT manufacturers and developers. The main barrier to entry now seems to be a basic understanding of electricity and electronics.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With 3d Printing</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/getting-started-with-3d-printing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/getting-started-with-3d-printing/</guid><description>The future is here! Right? 3D printing seems like something straight out of a science fiction movie, but is it everything we&amp;rsquo;ve dreamt it could be? In short, no. Not yet. Jumping in to 3D printing can be a very frustrating and disheartening experience, but with patience, and the right set of expectations, it can be a very fun and fulfilling device to have in the house or office. In this session I&amp;rsquo;ll help equip you for your small step into the future, and share my experience with it so that you may learn from my failures and eventual success.</description></item><item><title>HTTP interfaces for PHP</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/http-interfaces-for-php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/http-interfaces-for-php/</guid><description>While built for the web, PHP doesn&amp;rsquo;t abstract the actual HTTP messages. The new PSR-7 specification defines these, allowing you to code to shared interfaces instead of specific frameworks. Additionally, strong, shared HTTP abstractions give rise to a concept called &amp;ldquo;Middleware,&amp;rdquo; software that sits between a request and a response. Come discover how PSR-7 works, learn about common middleware patterns, and discover how the two will change how you develop in PHP!</description></item><item><title>HTTP/2: What You Need to Know</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/http-2-what-you-need-to-know/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/http-2-what-you-need-to-know/</guid><description>The HTTP protocol is now over 15 years old and it has served us well, but a new version will address some of the fundamental problems with how it was implemented “on the wire.” The changes are based on experience with Google’s SPDY protocol, but standardized for everyone to use. Major features of the current version such as methods and status codes will be unaffected. Existing sites should just work with the latest version, but they can drop many of the old tricks they used to squeeze out performance like CSS Sprites and file bundling.</description></item><item><title>Hour of Code</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/hour-of-code/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/hour-of-code/</guid><description>Hour of Code - This program is designed to demystify code and show that anybody can learn the basics. This is a beginner workshop for Geeklings who have no experience with programming. Every kid should have the opportunity to learn computer science. The Hour of Code is a global movement reaching tens of millions of students in 180+countries, and I am bringing it right here to Code Camp. No experience necessary!</description></item><item><title>Intro to ASP.NET WebAPI 2</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/intro-to-aspnet-webapi-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/intro-to-aspnet-webapi-2/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 2015 and your data needs to be consumed by multiple platforms. It only makes sense to move your data access and business logic into a centralized layer that can be shared. Topics we&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to touch on include Routing, OData, CORS, Security, Authentication, Authorization, Media Formatters, Model Validation and Versioning.</description></item><item><title>Making Git Work for You</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/making-git-work-for-you/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/making-git-work-for-you/</guid><description>Are you using Git but are worried you aren&amp;rsquo;t leveraging it as much as you could? Why do I care about merge vs. rebase? I pulled some bad code from a coworker that broke everything! How do I use reflog to time jump back to the good state I was in before? What&amp;rsquo;s an interactive rebase and how do I squash commits? I have legacy code in SVN/Mercurial, how can I get it into Git while preserving commit history?</description></item><item><title>Orchestration and Configuration Management With Ansible</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/orchestration-and-configuration-management-with-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/orchestration-and-configuration-management-with-ansible/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to set up development environments. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to configure servers. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to manage service and application dependencies. It&amp;rsquo;s even harder to maintain those things in a consistent way over time, especially with a team. It&amp;rsquo;s hardest to document things.
Configuration management and orchestration are ways of easing the pain. This talk will introduce Ansible, an open source IT automation tool. It will cover some good uses, bad uses, wins, and pitfalls.</description></item><item><title>PostCSS: A Dumb Name For an Awesome Thing</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/postcss-a-dumb-name-for-an-awesome-thing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/postcss-a-dumb-name-for-an-awesome-thing/</guid><description>CSS preprocessors have revealed to front-end developers the shortcomings of CSS. But there was a catch: you had to choose your language and stick with it. Would you go Sass? Or try LESS? Was Stylus your flavor? PostCSS, built on Node, is a CSS transforming engine that lets you choose (and write) the plugins that you need (or want) to take your styling source files and turn them into CSS. It&amp;rsquo;s fast; it&amp;rsquo;s flexible; it&amp;rsquo;s awesome.</description></item><item><title>Push/Pull: Or how to avoid idle talk</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/push-pull-or-how-to-avoid-idle-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/push-pull-or-how-to-avoid-idle-talk/</guid><description>This presentation is an exploration of the web of human and computer interaction we find around us and how that relates to the precious time available to our users and computer systems. The talk will begin with an overview of common communications and how they manifest themselves as use cases in our applications, websites and devices, followed by a look at how prevalent network patterns and tools can be applied to those communication use cases.</description></item><item><title>Robust Javascript</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/robust-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/robust-javascript/</guid><description>Javascript is nearly unavoidable in development. Either you&amp;rsquo;re a web developer using it on the client, server, or both, you have a third party system that happens to have chosen it for their integration language, or you&amp;rsquo;re doing some crazy embedded IoT thing and decided it makes sense there for whatever reason. In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll go over some common practices for solving problems related to maintainability, security, and stability.</description></item><item><title>Software Architecture Made Easy</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/software-architecture-made-easy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/software-architecture-made-easy/</guid><description>Software architecture is often taught as a series of principals used to define and describe the structures and interactions in a software system. While understanding the theory behind good design is essential often overlooked is the actual implementation of those principals. We know that we should separate concerns, but what does that look like in an actual, working solution? In this session we will talk about good architecture and, more importantly, bridge the theory/practice gap with real life examples.</description></item><item><title>The Resilient Web</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/the-resilient-web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/the-resilient-web/</guid><description>With access to the newest devices and fast, reliable Wi-Fi networks while developing, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget the havoc the real world can inflict on our web applications. Progressive enhancement, support vs optimization, and understanding the layers of the web can help us build resilient sites that work great — even on the crappiest of hotel Wi-Fi networks.</description></item><item><title>Using Visual Studio Online&#39;s new build system to achieve a Continuous Delivery pipeline</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/using-visual-studio-onlines-new-build-system-to-achieve-a-continuous-delivery-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 12:42:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sessions/using-visual-studio-onlines-new-build-system-to-achieve-a-continuous-delivery-pipeline/</guid><description>Visual Studio Online and TFS 2015 have introduced a new build system that has a web UI which Microsoft suggests to use rather than the XAML configuration of old. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a brief overview of an example of a continuous delivery pipeline and we&amp;rsquo;ll build it in VSO. By the end of the session, we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to run Unit tests, deploy to Azure Websites, run a UI test and deploy to staging all after pushing a code change to the Git repository on VSO.</description></item><item><title>Venue</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/venue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 11:27:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/venue/</guid><description>The next South Dakota Code Camp will be happening on November 7, 2015 at Southeast Technical Institute in the Sullivan Health Science Center. Click here for directions.</description></item><item><title>Sponsors</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sponsors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 11:27:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/sponsors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Speakers</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 11:27:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/speakers/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/schedule/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 11:27:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://2015.southdakotacodecamp.com/schedule/</guid><description> Saturday, November 7th</description></item></channel></rss>